Akash Panchal

Software Engineer

Lifelong learner and software engineer with 5 years of experience designing, implementing and debugging microservices-based project components. Hands-on experience of working on the cross-platform communication flaws, availability and performance issues in the cloud. Excited to grow and learn new languages, frameworks and architectures. A regular contributor to Github and Medium.



Work History

2018-12 - present

Software Engineer - Secure Home Platform

McAfee, Bengaluru

Working as a Cloud Software Engineer to provide custom SHP solution to an ISP partner. SHP Cloud is the backbone of the security system which governs the router and the mobile features.

- Reduced the partner-specific changes by 50% by generalizing the custom changes in the core solution
- Fixed the critical subscription failure cases that led to DDOS-like attack from routers
- Implemented scalable custom feature-set module to support different router models and versions
- Decreased the DB storage and Network calls up to 40% for a Router API by optimizing data flow design.

2017-11 - 2018-12

Software Engineer - Safe Connect

McAfee, Bengaluru

Safe Connect is a security App that provides secure network access using VPN service.

- Created the VPN interfaces for the end-product (Android) to consume
- Developed custom Network state-machine to support Auto-start VPN and Activity-log features

2016-06

Software Engineer - Mobile Apps Scanner

- 2017-10

McAfee, Bengaluru

- Increased the capacity of the app scanner by reducing repeat scanning of the Android Apps up to 5000 per day
- Proposed and demonstrated the POC App for behaviour analysis of background services

2015-06

- 2016-05

Intern - Bluetooth Engineering

Broadcom Inc, Bengaluru

- Implemented service layer for AVRCP 1.6 CoverArt within 1 month of the development cycle
- Developed a utility code to test BLE only APIs via Mobile App by reverse engineering AOSP code
- Supported the Bluetooth stack migration from the Android N to Android M codebase.



Education

2014-07 - 2016-05

Nirma University, Ahmedabad

M. Tech, Computer Science

Personal Info

Website

https://akashpanchal.com

Email

akashp1712@gmail.com

Phone

8722513026

LinkedIn

https://linkedin.com/in/akashp1712

GitHub

https://github.com/akashp1712

Address

A4, 4th cross, Bellandur main road, Bellandur, Bengaluru - 560103



Python

Android (Java)

Javascript

Cloud computing

Problem solving

Side Projects

Pythonizr

https://pythonizr.com

Pythonizr generates boilerplate code for the machine learning development.

Webpage Summarization

https://git.io/JG42M

Python cheat sheets

https://git.io/JG4aB

Medium Articles

https://akashp1712.medium.com